<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vladimir Korzinov</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Vladimir Korzinov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vvkorz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Links &amp; Books</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/links/</guid><description>Here is a collection of links and books that I ever found interesting and don&amp;rsquo;t want to forget.
Computer Science Introduction to Algorithms by T. H. Cormen, C. E. Leiserson, R.L. Rivest, &amp;amp; C. Stein Clean Code by Robert C. Martin Deep Learning by Y.Goodfellow, Y Bengio &amp;amp; A. Courville Designing Data-Intensive Applications Missing Semester of Your CS Education algorithmsbook.com The Twelve-Factor App Data Science at the Command Line Design Patterns.</description></item><item><title>Piet Mondrian generative art in Go</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/mondrian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/mondrian/</guid><description>A Mondrian image generator in Go takes a canvas of a certain size and divides it into partitions, thus creating a Piet Mondrian inspired image with primary colored rectangles. The partition complexity can be varied and can greatly change how your resulting image looks like. To learn more about the partition complexity and the algorithmic approach, check out section &amp;ldquo;Algorithm description&amp;rdquo;.
The Mondrian generator has the possibility to generate two styles of Mondrian-inspired images:</description></item><item><title>Magic mirror</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</guid><description>This is my private version of the magic mirror. The code is a well known open source project from MichMich. Here is how the assembley process and final result looked like:</description></item><item><title>Attendance system to track home office hours</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/rfid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/rfid/</guid><description>Here is an attendance system that I build in times of COVID-19 isolation in home office. I needed a way to track my working hours. It uses Raspberry Pi, RFID antenna and my private Dropbox to save a csv with my hours.
The code can be found on the github
The work is inspired by this post and this post.
Requirements pandas SPI-Py MFRC522-python</description></item><item><title>Abstract economics model of knowledge generation</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/economics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/economics/</guid><description>This is theoretical work in innovation economics and economics of technology. The work was done in the Institute for Economics (ECON) in Karlsruhe Institute of Technology together with PD Dr. Ivan Savi under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Ingrid Ott.
The idea was to model forces that might lead to the appearance of so called general purpose technology (GPT) in the economy. One can think of electricity or information and communication technology (IT) as examples.</description></item><item><title>Patent classification with Support Vector Machines</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/patents/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/patents/</guid><description>This is one of my first projects making use of machine learning for text classification. In order to analyse technological innovations in Germany for my PhD thesis, robotics patents were classified into service and industrial classes. You can find a detailed description and results in the following paper . The project was done in the Institute for Economics ( ECON ) in Karlsruhe Institute of Technology together with Dr. Florian H.</description></item><item><title>Master Thesis</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/masters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/masters/</guid><description>This project focused on the detection of factors influencing collaboration among academic institutions in the field of nanotechnology. More than 300.000 publications were analysed together with supplementary data to predict the appearence of collaboration links among organisations working in nanotechnology field in Germany.
I used negative binomial and logistic regressions predicting co-authorship links. This work was done at the Faculty of Technology Policy and Management of the Delft University of Technology and published in the Journal of Evolutionary Economics.</description></item><item><title>Engineering degree in BMSTU</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/diploma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/diploma/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the account of my journey to earning an engineering degree from Bauman Moscow State Technical University (BMSTU).
My thesis, titled &amp;ldquo;Vacuum Evaporation Machine for Osmium Films,&amp;rdquo; encapsulated the culmination of my studies. Throughout the final two years of my education in Moscow, I devoted all my term papers to various components of this intricate system, documented solely in Russian. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief overview of the machine.
The primary objective was to overhaul an existing vacuum apparatus, salvaging only the core chamber along with its accompanying units and technical elements, while reimagining the vacuum system entirely.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/index-about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/index-about/</guid><description>Welcome to my website!
My name is Vladimir and I am an engineer currently focusing on building and operationalising machine learning solutions in manufacturing industry.
In my free time I enjoy spending time with my family and dog Yoki as well as geeking out with Raspbery Pis</description></item></channel></rss>