<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vladimir K</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Vladimir K</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vvkorz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Friedrich Duerrenmatt's Plays and Books</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/literature_duerrenmatt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/literature_duerrenmatt/</guid><description>Recently, I discovered a new author for myself: Friedrich Duerrenmatt. He was a Swiss author and dramatist in XX century. So far I red three of his books and quite enjoyed all of them:
The Physicists. I recommend to read it in german, if possible. It is a satiric drama that reflects on the times of the Cold War. Apparently, this is one of the most played theater pieces in German speaking Switzerland, Germany and Austria.</description></item><item><title>Links &amp; Books</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/links/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/links/</guid><description>Here is a collection of links and books that I ever found interesting and don&amp;rsquo;t want to forget.
Computer Science Introduction to Algorithms by T. H. Cormen, C. E. Leiserson, R.L. Rivest, &amp;amp; C. Stein Clean Code by Robert C. Martin Deep Learning by Y.Goodfellow, Y Bengio &amp;amp; A. Courville Designing Data-Intensive Applications Missing Semester of Your CS Education algorithmsbook.com The Twelve-Factor App Data Science at the Command Line Design Patterns.</description></item><item><title>Dog stats</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/dogpeepoo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/dogpeepoo/</guid><description>Dog stats If you ever consider of getting a dog, this page might help you estimate how much to expect in the first year. We bought a dog in October 2023 and called her Yoki. Here is the picture of the beast:
From the start we decided to scientifically approach the training process and track her activities. The question was where to track them? After searching for out-of-the-box solutions in the Web, Playstore and Android I decided to make my own Android app to track her pee and poo events.</description></item><item><title>Piet Mondrian generative art in Go</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/mondrian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/mondrian/</guid><description>A Mondrian image generator in Go takes a canvas of a certain size and divides it into partitions, thus creating a Piet Mondrian inspired image with primary colored rectangles. The partition complexity can be varied and can greatly change how your resulting image looks like. To learn more about the partition complexity and the algorithmic approach, check out section &amp;ldquo;Algorithm description&amp;rdquo;.
The Mondrian generator has the possibility to generate two styles of Mondrian-inspired images:</description></item><item><title>Magic mirror</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</guid><description>This is my private version of the magic mirror. The code is a well known open source project from MichMich. Here is how the assembley process and final result looked like:</description></item><item><title>RFID based hours tracking system</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/rfid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/rfid/</guid><description>During COVID-19 isolation in home office I needed some refreshment in my daily routine. In order to get a feeling of &amp;ldquo;going to work&amp;rdquo; I took a walk in the morning around my place and then &amp;ldquo;cheked in&amp;rdquo; to start my day.
In order to have a very authentic feeling I have build a small system to check-in with my work rfid card. I used Raspberry Pi, RFID antenna (MFRC522-python), SPI-Py and Dropbox API to save files with my hours.</description></item><item><title>Abstract economics model of knowledge generation</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/economics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/economics/</guid><description>This is theoretical work in innovation economics and economics of technology. The work was done in the Institute for Economics (ECON) in Karlsruhe Institute of Technology together with PD Dr. Ivan Savin under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Ingrid Ott.
The idea was to model forces that might lead to the appearance of so called general purpose technology (GPT) in the economy. One can think of electricity or information and communication technology (IT) as examples.</description></item><item><title>Patent classification with Support Vector Machines</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/patents/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/patents/</guid><description>This is one of my first projects making use of machine learning for text classification. In order to analyse technological innovations in Germany for my PhD thesis, robotics patents were classified into service and industrial classes. You can find a detailed description and results in the following paper. The project was done in the Institute for Economics ECON in Karlsruhe Institute of Technology together with Dr. Florian H. Kreuchauff under the supervision of the Prof.</description></item><item><title>Master Thesis</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/masters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/masters/</guid><description>This project focused on the detection of factors influencing collaboration among academic institutions in the field of nanotechnology. More than 300.000 publications were analysed together with supplementary data to predict the appearence of collaboration links among organisations working in nanotechnology field in Germany.
I used negative binomial and logistic regressions predicting co-authorship links. This work was done at the Faculty of Technology Policy and Management of the Delft University of Technology and published in the Journal of Evolutionary Economics.</description></item><item><title>Engineering degree in BMSTU</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/diploma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/diploma/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the account of my journey to earning an engineering degree from Bauman Moscow State Technical University (BMSTU).
My thesis, titled &amp;ldquo;Vacuum Evaporation Machine for Osmium Films,&amp;rdquo; encapsulated the culmination of my studies. Throughout the final two years of my education in Moscow, I devoted all my term papers to various components of this intricate system, documented solely in Russian. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief overview of the machine.
The primary objective was to overhaul an existing vacuum apparatus, salvaging only the core chamber along with its accompanying units and technical elements, while reimagining the vacuum system entirely.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/index-about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/index-about/</guid><description>Hi, I’m Vladimir! I’m an engineer specializing in creating and deploying machine learning solutions for the manufacturing industry. In my free time, I love hanging out with my family and my dog, Yoki, and tinkering with Raspberry Pis.
This is where I share my projects, ideas, and thoughts on different topics. Whether you’re here to check out my work, connect, or learn more about me, I’m happy you’re here. Let’s get started!</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/license/</guid><description>This blog is distributed under the Creative Commons - Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International license. This means that you can read the blog on anything you like and wherever you like, keep it with you, give it away to friends and colleagues and even publish it on your websites/blogs. However, you should explicitly mention a link to original site vvkorz.github.io.
No modifications, mixes or other additional creativity may be made with texts or graphics.</description></item></channel></rss>