<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Vladimir Korzinov</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Vladimir Korzinov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Friedrich Duerrenmatt's Plays and Books</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/literature_duerrenmatt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/literature_duerrenmatt/</guid><description>Recently, I discovered a new author for myself: Friedrich Duerrenmatt. He was a Swiss author and dramatist in XX century. So far I red three of his books and quite enjoyed all of them:
The Physicists. I recommend to read it in german, if possible. It is a satiric drama that reflects on the times of the Cold War. Apparently, this is one of the most played theater pieces in German speaking Switzerland, Germany and Austria.</description></item><item><title>Links &amp; Books</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/links/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/links/</guid><description>Here is a collection of links and books that I ever found interesting and don&amp;rsquo;t want to forget.
Computer Science Introduction to Algorithms by T. H. Cormen, C. E. Leiserson, R.L. Rivest, &amp;amp; C. Stein Clean Code by Robert C. Martin Deep Learning by Y.Goodfellow, Y Bengio &amp;amp; A. Courville Designing Data-Intensive Applications Missing Semester of Your CS Education algorithmsbook.com The Twelve-Factor App Data Science at the Command Line Design Patterns.</description></item><item><title>Dog stats</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/dogpeepoo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/dogpeepoo/</guid><description>Dog stats If you ever consider of getting a dog, this page might help you estimate how much to expect in the first year. We bought a dog in October 2023 and called her Yoki. Here is the picture of the beast:
From the start we decided to scientifically approach the training process and track her activities. The question was where to track them? After searching for out-of-the-box solutions in the Web, Playstore and Android I decided to make my own Android app to track her pee and poo events.</description></item><item><title>Magic mirror</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</guid><description>This is my private version of the magic mirror. The code is a well known open source project from MichMich. Here is how the assembley process and final result looked like:</description></item></channel></rss>