<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Vladimir K</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/tags/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Vladimir K</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vvkorz.github.io/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal projects</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Some stuff I did during my studies:
Engineering degree Master&amp;rsquo;s degree Economics modelling Patent classification Long weekends&amp;hellip;:
Mondrian like pictures in Go Office hours tracking</description></item><item><title>Piet Mondrian generative art in Go</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/mondrian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/mondrian/</guid><description>A Mondrian image generator in Go takes a canvas of a certain size and divides it into partitions, thus creating a Piet Mondrian inspired image with primary colored rectangles. The partition complexity can be varied and can greatly change how your resulting image looks like. To learn more about the partition complexity and the algorithmic approach, check out section &amp;ldquo;Algorithm description&amp;rdquo;.
The Mondrian generator has the possibility to generate two styles of Mondrian-inspired images:</description></item><item><title>Magic mirror</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/posts/magicmirror/</guid><description>This is my private version of the magic mirror. The code is a well known open source project from MichMich. Here is how the assembley process and final result looked like:</description></item><item><title>RFID based hours tracking system</title><link>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/rfid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vvkorz.github.io/projects/rfid/</guid><description>During COVID-19 isolation in home office I needed some refreshment in my daily routine. In order to get a feeling of &amp;ldquo;going to work&amp;rdquo; I took a walk in the morning around my place and then &amp;ldquo;cheked in&amp;rdquo; to start my day.
In order to have a very authentic feeling I have build a small system to check-in with my work rfid card. I used Raspberry Pi, RFID antenna (MFRC522-python), SPI-Py and Dropbox API to save files with my hours.</description></item></channel></rss>